Denitsa Georgieva

REACT AND REDUX ENGINEER

xdenitsax@gmail.com • 224-421-6819 • Boulder, CO • https://denitsa.co

Summary

Front end developer with 3+ years of experience, Karate black belt and gold medalist in the US and Europe. Organized and committed team player with strong analytical skills and knowledge to build large scale apps from start to finish.

Experience

Frontend Developer - full-time | September 2021 - present

Aura: https://www.aura.com

- Maintained and developed a web app used by hundreds of thousands of users
- Mentored and guided junior devs through React/Redux development pattern
- Worked in a team of 15 devs using GitHub, Jira, Slack software
- Wrote acceptance criteria and documentation for QA and dev team members
- Wrote custom React Hooks, reusable components, used React Context
- Converted legacy |S code to Typescript
- Wrote and maintained unit tests using Jest
- Used Redux Toolkit for state management and Thunks for asynchronous actions
- Received recognition from leaders and colleagues for results and collaboration.
- Collaborated with UI/UX designers to find the best solution
- Actively participated in product and Scrum/Agile meetings and ceremonies
- Encouraged team members to improve communication and involvement
- Wrote maintainable, scalable, reusable and performant code

Frontend Developer - contractor | February 2019 - September 2021

BluedgeUSA: https://www.bluedgeusa.com

- Maintained 4 E-Commerce websites with gross monthly revenue of \$1 million
- Used Shopify templating engine, Javascript and HTML to build features
- Used Bootstrap 5 and SCSS to style website components
- Resolved bugs/ technical issues in a timely manner
- Communicated with clients and designers to work out feature implementation

Other Projects

- Created 3+ websites with 4-week average delivery time
- Built 2+ apps using React/Redux/NodeJS
- Set up and configured CI/CD pipeline on AWS
- Built majority of websites using HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript(ES5-ES6)
- Used redux-thunks for asynchronous CRUD operations
- Used react-router-dom for building app navigation
- Used CSS flexbox to create responsive layout for different sized screens.

Skills

Languages

- JavaScript (ES5, ES6)
- HTML5
- CSS3, SCSS, Sass

Libraries & Frameworks

- React
- Redux
- Redux-toolkit
- Node.js
- React-router-dom
- Lodash
- TypeScript
- Semantic UI
- Styled-components
- Framer Motion

Technologies & Tools

- RESTful API
- Babel, Webpack
- GraphQL
- Webpack
- lest, Mocha
- Mongo.db
- AWS
- Github
- Shopify
- Figma

Achievements

- Black Belt in Karate Kyokushin
- US & European gold medalist

Education

Burgas Free University 2013 - 2018 Burgas, Bulgaria Bachelor in Law